# VALENTINA BERNAL GOMEZ

# Human Resources | Data Analytics | Health & Safety Specialist

0899 - 709 - 041 | valentinabernal97@gmail.com | Dublin

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Dedicated Industrial Engineer with a passion for human resources. 1 year of experience effectively recruting top talent. Confident in ability to define role requirements and lead the interview process. Committed to continuous improvement and impacting team success.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Human Resources
- Quantitative Analysis
- Critical thinking

- Data Analysis (SQL, Python)
- Requirements Definition
- Training and Mentoring

- Problem Solving
- Data Visualizations
- Safety Audits

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **BILINGUAL CALL CENTER AGENT**

ContactPoint Co. | October 2022 - December 2022

- Support business growth by upselling/cross selling as the opportunity arises.
- Contribute the team and department performance through meeting your agreed weekly targets.
- Manage customer complaints effectively, offering suitable solutions and alternatives within specified time limits, and diligently follow up to ensure resolution.
- Address and resolve a managed portfolio of customer issues and concerns related to sales and service reliability.

#### OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY SPECIALIST

Redeban Co. | December 2020 - March 2022

- Create, enact, and oversee environmental, health, and safety (EHS) programs to guarantee adherence to government regulations, company technical standards, and our core values.
- Recognize areas of potential risk by analyzing audit outcomes, and provide immediate coaching and guidance to address issues as they arise in real-time.
- Assist in conducting EHS training and orientations for new hires, regular refresher training for existing staff, and the delivery of EHS-related training programs to all levels within the organization.
- Support the on-site EHS incident management process, overseeing EHS incidents through to resolution, which includes conducting root cause analysis.

# **ACQUISITION AND DEVELOPMENT TRAINEE INTERN**

Redeban Co. | June 2020 - December 2020

- Collaborate with hiring managers to define role requirements, identify effective recruitment channels, source and screen candidates, conduct interviews, and assess their suitability.
- Utilize a wide range of online and offline sources, such as social networks, executive recruitment, and networking channels, to identify and attract top talent to the organization.
- Lead and manage the interview process in coordination with stakeholders, including conducting post-interview evaluations with hiring managers
- Collaborate on talent management and talent acquisition projects associated with attracting, developing, and retaining a diverse global workforce.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **GENERAL ENGLISH B2+**

International School Of English | Ireland | January 2023 - July 2023

#### **BACHELOR OF INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING**

The Julio Garavito School of Engineering | Colombia | August 2015 - March 2021

# **HIGH SCHOOL**

The Colsubsidio Ciudadela School | Colombia | November 2013